<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Beautiful Speeches</title>
    <description>Speeches are some of the most beautiful works of art that humans have made. Beautiful Speeches aims to consolidate the greatest speeches into one site. Beyond collecting speeches, Beautiful Speeches endeavors to create a clean interface so that each word resonates on the page.</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:51:35 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2014 00:51:35 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.2.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Words matter</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Understand this argument about words not mattering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important thing that we can do right now is to re-engage the American people in the process of governance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get them excited and interested again in what works and what can work in our government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make politics cool again. And important again. And relevant again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t tell me words don&amp;#39;t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream - just words?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We owe these truths to be self-evident that all men are created equal - just words?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have nothing to fear but fear itself - just words, just speeches?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s true that speeches don&amp;#39;t solve all problems. But what is also true is if we cannot inspire the country to believe again, then it doesn&amp;#39;t matter how many policies and plans we have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that why I&amp;#39;m running for President of the United States of America. And that&amp;#39;s why we just won eight elections straight. Because the American people want to believe in change again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t tell me words don&amp;#39;t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t tell me ideals and inspiration don&amp;#39;t matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;#39;t tell me hope doesn&amp;#39;t matter.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2013 01:03:28 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/2013/06/28/words-matter/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/2013/06/28/words-matter/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>I have a dream</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am happy to join with you today in what will go down in history as the greatest demonstration for freedom in the history of our nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Five score years ago, a great American, in whose symbolic shadow we stand today, signed the Emancipation Proclamation. This momentous decree came as a great beacon light of hope to millions of Negro slaves who had been seared in the flames of withering injustice. It came as a joyous daybreak to end the long night of their captivity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But one hundred years later, the Negro still is not free. One hundred years later, the life of the Negro is still sadly crippled by the manacles of segregation and the chains of discrimination. One hundred years later, the Negro lives on a lonely island of poverty in the midst of a vast ocean of material prosperity. One hundred years later, the Negro is still languished in the corners of American society and finds himself an exile in his own land. And so we&amp;#39;ve come here today to dramatize a shameful condition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a sense we&amp;#39;ve come to our nation&amp;#39;s capital to cash a check. When the architects of our republic wrote the magnificent words of the Constitution and the Declaration of Independence, they were signing a promissory note to which every American was to fall heir. This note was a promise that all men, yes, black men as well as white men, would be guaranteed the &amp;quot;unalienable Rights&amp;quot; of &amp;quot;Life, Liberty and the pursuit of Happiness.&amp;quot; It is obvious today that America has defaulted on this promissory note, insofar as her citizens of color are concerned. Instead of honoring this sacred obligation, America has given the Negro people a bad check, a check which has come back marked &amp;quot;insufficient funds.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we refuse to believe that the bank of justice is bankrupt. We refuse to believe that there are insufficient funds in the great vaults of opportunity of this nation. And so, we&amp;#39;ve come to cash this check, a check that will give us upon demand the riches of freedom and the security of justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have also come to this hallowed spot to remind America of the fierce urgency of Now. This is no time to engage in the luxury of cooling off or to take the tranquilizing drug of gradualism. Now is the time to make real the promises of democracy. Now is the time to rise from the dark and desolate valley of segregation to the sunlit path of racial justice. Now is the time to lift our nation from the quicksands of racial injustice to the solid rock of brotherhood. Now is the time to make justice a reality for all of God&amp;#39;s children.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be fatal for the nation to overlook the urgency of the moment. This sweltering summer of the Negro&amp;#39;s legitimate discontent will not pass until there is an invigorating autumn of freedom and equality. Nineteen sixty-three is not an end, but a beginning. And those who hope that the Negro needed to blow off steam and will now be content will have a rude awakening if the nation returns to business as usual. And there will be neither rest nor tranquility in America until the Negro is granted his citizenship rights. The whirlwinds of revolt will continue to shake the foundations of our nation until the bright day of justice emerges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is something that I must say to my people, who stand on the warm threshold which leads into the palace of justice: In the process of gaining our rightful place, we must not be guilty of wrongful deeds. Let us not seek to satisfy our thirst for freedom by drinking from the cup of bitterness and hatred. We must forever conduct our struggle on the high plane of dignity and discipline. We must not allow our creative protest to degenerate into physical violence. Again and again, we must rise to the majestic heights of meeting physical force with soul force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The marvelous new militancy which has engulfed the Negro community must not lead us to a distrust of all white people, for many of our white brothers, as evidenced by their presence here today, have come to realize that their destiny is tied up with our destiny. And they have come to realize that their freedom is inextricably bound to our freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot walk alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as we walk, we must make the pledge that we shall always march ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cannot turn back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are those who are asking the devotees of civil rights, &amp;quot;When will you be satisfied?&amp;quot; We can never be satisfied as long as the Negro is the victim of the unspeakable horrors of police brutality. We can never be satisfied as long as our bodies, heavy with the fatigue of travel, cannot gain lodging in the motels of the highways and the hotels of the cities. We cannot be satisfied as long as the negro&amp;#39;s basic mobility is from a smaller ghetto to a larger one. We can never be satisfied as long as our children are stripped of their self-hood and robbed of their dignity by signs stating: &amp;quot;For Whites Only.&amp;quot; We cannot be satisfied as long as a Negro in Mississippi cannot vote and a Negro in New York believes he has nothing for which to vote. No, no, we are not satisfied, and we will not be satisfied until &amp;quot;justice rolls down like waters, and righteousness like a mighty stream.&amp;quot;ยน&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not unmindful that some of you have come here out of great trials and tribulations. Some of you have come fresh from narrow jail cells. And some of you have come from areas where your quest -- quest for freedom left you battered by the storms of persecution and staggered by the winds of police brutality. You have been the veterans of creative suffering. Continue to work with the faith that unearned suffering is redemptive. Go back to Mississippi, go back to Alabama, go back to South Carolina, go back to Georgia, go back to Louisiana, go back to the slums and ghettos of our northern cities, knowing that somehow this situation can and will be changed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us not wallow in the valley of despair, I say to you today, my friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so even though we face the difficulties of today and tomorrow, I still have a dream. It is a dream deeply rooted in the American dream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream that one day this nation will rise up and live out the true meaning of its creed: &amp;quot;We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are created equal.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream that one day on the red hills of Georgia, the sons of former slaves and the sons of former slave owners will be able to sit down together at the table of brotherhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream that one day even the state of Mississippi, a state sweltering with the heat of injustice, sweltering with the heat of oppression, will be transformed into an oasis of freedom and justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream that my four little children will one day live in a nation where they will not be judged by the color of their skin but by the content of their character.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream that one day, down in Alabama, with its vicious racists, with its governor having his lips dripping with the words of &amp;quot;interposition&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;nullification&amp;quot; -- one day right there in Alabama little black boys and black girls will be able to join hands with little white boys and white girls as sisters and brothers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a dream that one day every valley shall be exalted, and every hill and mountain shall be made low, the rough places will be made plain, and the crooked places will be made straight; &amp;quot;and the glory of the Lord shall be revealed and all flesh shall see it together.&amp;quot;2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is our hope, and this is the faith that I go back to the South with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this faith, we will be able to hew out of the mountain of despair a stone of hope. With this faith, we will be able to transform the jangling discords of our nation into a beautiful symphony of brotherhood. With this faith, we will be able to work together, to pray together, to struggle together, to go to jail together, to stand up for freedom together, knowing that we will be free one day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this will be the day -- this will be the day when all of God&amp;#39;s children will be able to sing with new meaning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My country &amp;#39;tis of thee, sweet land of liberty, of thee I sing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Land where my fathers died, land of the Pilgrim&amp;#39;s pride,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From every mountainside, let freedom ring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if America is to be a great nation, this must become true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And so let freedom ring from the prodigious hilltops of New Hampshire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let freedom ring from the mighty mountains of New York.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let freedom ring from the heightening Alleghenies of Pennsylvania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let freedom ring from the snow-capped Rockies of Colorado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let freedom ring from the curvaceous slopes of California.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not only that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let freedom ring from Stone Mountain of Georgia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let freedom ring from Lookout Mountain of Tennessee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let freedom ring from every hill and molehill of Mississippi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From every mountainside, let freedom ring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when this happens, and when we allow freedom ring, when we let it ring from every village and every hamlet, from every state and every city, we will be able to speed up that day when all of God&amp;#39;s children, black men and white men, Jews and Gentiles, Protestants and Catholics, will be able to join hands and sing in the words of the old Negro spiritual:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free at last! Free at last!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank God Almighty, we are free at last!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 1963 00:03:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/1963/08/29/i-have-a-dream/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/1963/08/29/i-have-a-dream/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ich bin ein Berliner</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I am proud to come to this city as the guest of your distinguished Mayor, who has symbolized throughout the world the fighting spirit of West Berlin. And I am proud to visit the Federal Republic with your distinguished Chancellor who for so many years has committed Germany to democracy and freedom and progress, and to come here in the company of my fellow American, General Clay, who has been in this city during its great moments of crisis and will come again if ever needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two thousand years ago the proudest boast was &amp;quot;civis Romanus sum.&amp;quot; Today, in the world of freedom, the proudest boast is &amp;quot;Ich bin ein Berliner.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I appreciate my interpreter translating my German!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many people in the world who really don&amp;#39;t understand, or say they don&amp;#39;t, what is the great issue between the free world and the Communist world. Let them come to Berlin. There are some who say that communism is the wave of the future. Let them come to Berlin. And there are some who say in Europe and elsewhere we can work with the Communists. Let them come to Berlin. And there are even a few who say that it is true that communism is an evil system, but it permits us to make economic progress. Lass&amp;#39; sie nach Berlin kommen. Let them come to Berlin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom has many difficulties and democracy is not perfect, but we have never had to put a wall up to keep our people in, to prevent them from leaving us. I want to say, on behalf of my countrymen, who live many miles away on the other side of the Atlantic, who are far distant from you, that they take the greatest pride that they have been able to share with you, even from a distance, the story of the last 18 years. I know of no town, no city, that has been besieged for 18 years that still lives with the vitality and the force, and the hope and the determination of the city of West Berlin. While the wall is the most obvious and vivid demonstration of the failures of the Communist system, for all the world to see, we take no satisfaction in it, for it is, as your Mayor has said, an offense not only against history but an offense against humanity, separating families, dividing husbands and wives and brothers and sisters, and dividing a people who wish to be joined together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is true of this city is true of Germany--real, lasting peace in Europe can never be assured as long as one German out of four is denied the elementary right of free men, and that is to make a free choice. In 18 years of peace and good faith, this generation of Germans has earned the right to be free, including the right to unite their families and their nation in lasting peace, with good will to all people. You live in a defended island of freedom, but your life is part of the main. So let me ask you as I close, to lift your eyes beyond the dangers of today, to the hopes of tomorrow, beyond the freedom merely of this city of Berlin, or your country of Germany, to the advance of freedom everywhere, beyond the wall to the day of peace with justice, beyond yourselves and ourselves to all mankind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Freedom is indivisible, and when one man is enslaved, all are not free. When all are free, then we can look forward to that day when this city will be joined as one and this country and this great Continent of Europe in a peaceful and hopeful globe. When that day finally comes, as it will, the people of West Berlin can take sober satisfaction in the fact that they were in the front lines for almost two decades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All free men, wherever they may live, are citizens of Berlin, and, therefore, as a free man, I take pride in the words &amp;quot;Ich bin ein Berliner.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 1963 00:03:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/1963/06/27/ich-bin-ein-berliner/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/1963/06/27/ich-bin-ein-berliner/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nobel Peace Prize Acceptance Speech</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ladies and gentlemen,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that this award was not made to me as a man, but to my work - a life&amp;#39;s work in the agony and sweat of the human spirit, not for glory and least of all for profit, but to create out of the materials of the human spirit something which did not exist before. So this award is only mine in trust. It will not be difficult to find a dedication for the money part of it commensurate with the purpose and significance of its origin. But I would like to do the same with the acclaim too, by using this moment as a pinnacle from which I might be listened to by the young men and women already dedicated to the same anguish and travail, among whom is already that one who will some day stand here where I am standing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our tragedy today is a general and universal physical fear so long sustained by now that we can even bear it. There are no longer problems of the spirit. There is only the question: When will I be blown up? Because of this, the young man or woman writing today has forgotten the problems of the human heart in conflict with itself which alone can make good writing because only that is worth writing about, worth the agony and the sweat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He must learn them again. He must teach himself that the basest of all things is to be afraid; and, teaching himself that, forget it forever, leaving no room in his workshop for anything but the old verities and truths of the heart, the old universal truths lacking which any story is ephemeral and doomed - love and honor and pity and pride and compassion and sacrifice. Until he does so, he labors under a curse. He writes not of love but of lust, of defeats in which nobody loses anything of value, of victories without hope and, worst of all, without pity or compassion. His griefs grieve on no universal bones, leaving no scars. He writes not of the heart but of the glands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until he relearns these things, he will write as though he stood among and watched the end of man. I decline to accept the end of man. It is easy enough to say that man is immortal simply because he will endure: that when the last dingdong of doom has clanged and faded from the last worthless rock hanging tideless in the last red and dying evening, that even then there will still be one more sound: that of his puny inexhaustible voice, still talking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I refuse to accept this. I believe that man will not merely endure: he will prevail. He is immortal, not because he alone among creatures has an inexhaustible voice, but because he has a soul, a spirit capable of compassion and sacrifice and endurance. The poet&amp;#39;s, the writer&amp;#39;s, duty is to write about these things. It is his privilege to help man endure by lifting his heart, by reminding him of the courage and honor and hope and pride and compassion and pity and sacrifice which have been the glory of his past. The poet&amp;#39;s voice need not merely be the record of man, it can be one of the props, the pillars to help him endure and prevail.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 1950 00:03:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/1950/12/11/nobel-peace-prize-acceptance-speech/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/1950/12/11/nobel-peace-prize-acceptance-speech/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chief Joseph Surrenders</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Tell General Howard I know his heart. What he told me before, I have it in my heart. I am tired of fighting. Our Chiefs are killed; Looking Glass is dead, Ta Hool Hool Shute is dead. The old men are all dead. It is the young men who say yes or no. He who led on the young men is dead. It is cold, and we have no blankets; the little children are freezing to death. My people, some of them, have run away to the hills, and have no blankets, no food. No one knows where they are - perhaps freezing to death. I want to have time to look for my children, and see how many of them I can find. Maybe I shall find them among the dead. Hear me, my Chiefs! I am tired; my heart is sick and sad. From where the sun now stands I will fight no more forever.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 1877 01:03:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/1877/10/05/chief-joseph-surrender/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/1877/10/05/chief-joseph-surrender/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On women&#39;s right to vote</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Friends and fellow citizens: I stand before you tonight under indictment for the alleged crime of having voted at the last presidential election, without having a lawful right to vote. It shall be my work this evening to prove to you that in thus voting, I not only committed no crime, but, instead, simply exercised my citizen&amp;#39;s rights, guaranteed to me and all United States citizens by the National Constitution, beyond the power of any state to deny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The preamble of the Federal Constitution says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;We, the people of the United States, in order to form a more perfect union, establish justice, insure domestic tranquillity, provide for the common defense, promote the general welfare, and secure the blessings of liberty to ourselves and our posterity, do ordain and establish this Constitution for the United States of America.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was we, the people; not we, the white male citizens; nor yet we, the male citizens; but we, the whole people, who formed the Union. And we formed it, not to give the blessings of liberty, but to secure them; not to the half of ourselves and the half of our posterity, but to the whole people - women as well as men. And it is a downright mockery to talk to women of their enjoyment of the blessings of liberty while they are denied the use of the only means of securing them provided by this democratic-republican government - the ballot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For any state to make sex a qualification that must ever result in the disfranchisement of one entire half of the people, is to pass a bill of attainder, or, an ex post facto law, and is therefore a violation of the supreme law of the land. By it the blessings of liberty are forever withheld from women and their female posterity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To them this government has no just powers derived from the consent of the governed. To them this government is not a democracy. It is not a republic. It is an odious aristocracy; a hateful oligarchy of sex; the most hateful aristocracy ever established on the face of the globe; an oligarchy of wealth, where the rich govern the poor. An oligarchy of learning, where the educated govern the ignorant, or even an oligarchy of race, where the Saxon rules the African, might be endured; but this oligarchy of sex, which makes father, brothers, husband, sons, the oligarchs over the mother and sisters, the wife and daughters, of every household - which ordains all men sovereigns, all women subjects, carries dissension, discord, and rebellion into every home of the nation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Webster, Worcester, and Bouvier all define a citizen to be a person in the United States, entitled to vote and hold office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only question left to be settled now is: Are women persons? And I hardly believe any of our opponents will have the hardihood to say they are not. Being persons, then, women are citizens; and no state has a right to make any law, or to enforce any old law, that shall abridge their privileges or immunities. Hence, every discrimination against women in the constitutions and laws of the several states is today null and void, precisely as is every one against Negroes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 1872 00:03:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/1872/01/02/on-womens-right-to-vote/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/1872/01/02/on-womens-right-to-vote/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Gettysburg Address</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Four score and seven years ago our fathers brought forth on this continent, a new nation, conceived in Liberty, and dedicated to the proposition that all men are created equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we are engaged in a great civil war, testing whether that nation, or any nation so conceived and so dedicated, can long endure. We are met on a great battle-field of that war. We have come to dedicate a portion of that field, as a final resting place for those who here gave their lives that that nation might live. It is altogether fitting and proper that we should do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, in a larger sense, we can not dedicate -- we can not consecrate -- we can not hallow -- this ground. The brave men, living and dead, who struggled here, have consecrated it, far above our poor power to add or detract. The world will little note, nor long remember what we say here, but it can never forget what they did here. It is for us the living, rather, to be dedicated here to the unfinished work which they who fought here have thus far so nobly advanced. It is rather for us to be here dedicated to the great task remaining before us -- that from these honored dead we take increased devotion to that cause for which they gave the last full measure of devotion -- that we here highly resolve that these dead shall not have died in vain -- that this nation, under God, shall have a new birth of freedom -- and that government of the people, by the people, for the people, shall not perish from the earth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 1863 00:03:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/1863/11/20/the-gettysburg-address/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/1863/11/20/the-gettysburg-address/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Give me liberty or give me death</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;No man thinks more highly than I do of the patriotism, as well as abilities, of the very worthy gentlemen who have just addressed the House. But different men often see the same subject in different lights; and, therefore, I hope it will not be thought disrespectful to those gentlemen if, entertaining as I do opinions of a character very opposite to theirs, I shall speak forth my sentiments freely and without reserve. This is no time for ceremony. The question before the House is one of awful moment to this country. For my own part, I consider it as nothing less than a question of freedom or slavery; and in proportion to the magnitude of the subject ought to be the freedom of the debate. It is only in this way that we can hope to arrive at truth, and fulfill the great responsibility which we hold to God and our country. Should I keep back my opinions at such a time, through fear of giving offense, I should consider myself as guilty of treason towards my country, and of an act of disloyalty toward the Majesty of Heaven, which I revere above all earthly kings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. President, it is natural to man to indulge in the illusions of hope. We are apt to shut our eyes against a painful truth, and listen to the song of that siren till she transforms us into beasts. Is this the part of wise men, engaged in a great and arduous struggle for liberty? Are we disposed to be of the number of those who, having eyes, see not, and, having ears, hear not, the things which so nearly concern their temporal salvation? For my part, whatever anguish of spirit it may cost, I am willing to know the whole truth; to know the worst, and to provide for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have but one lamp by which my feet are guided, and that is the lamp of experience. I know of no way of judging of the future but by the past. And judging by the past, I wish to know what there has been in the conduct of the British ministry for the last ten years to justify those hopes with which gentlemen have been pleased to solace themselves and the House. Is it that insidious smile with which our petition has been lately received? Trust it not, sir; it will prove a snare to your feet. Suffer not yourselves to be betrayed with a kiss. Ask yourselves how this gracious reception of our petition comports with those warlike preparations which cover our waters and darken our land. Are fleets and armies necessary to a work of love and reconciliation? Have we shown ourselves so unwilling to be reconciled that force must be called in to win back our love? Let us not deceive ourselves, sir. These are the implements of war and subjugation; the last arguments to which kings resort. I ask gentlemen, sir, what means this martial array, if its purpose be not to force us to submission? Can gentlemen assign any other possible motive for it? Has Great Britain any enemy, in this quarter of the world, to call for all this accumulation of navies and armies? No, sir, she has none. They are meant for us: they can be meant for no other. They are sent over to bind and rivet upon us those chains which the British ministry have been so long forging. And what have we to oppose to them? Shall we try argument? Sir, we have been trying that for the last ten years. Have we anything new to offer upon the subject? Nothing. We have held the subject up in every light of which it is capable; but it has been all in vain. Shall we resort to entreaty and humble supplication? What terms shall we find which have not been already exhausted? Let us not, I beseech you, sir, deceive ourselves. Sir, we have done everything that could be done to avert the storm which is now coming on. We have petitioned; we have remonstrated; we have supplicated; we have prostrated ourselves before the throne, and have implored its interposition to arrest the tyrannical hands of the ministry and Parliament. Our petitions have been slighted; our remonstrances have produced additional violence and insult; our supplications have been disregarded; and we have been spurned, with contempt, from the foot of the throne! In vain, after these things, may we indulge the fond hope of peace and reconciliation. There is no longer any room for hope. If we wish to be free-- if we mean to preserve inviolate those inestimable privileges for which we have been so long contending--if we mean not basely to abandon the noble struggle in which we have been so long engaged, and which we have pledged ourselves never to abandon until the glorious object of our contest shall be obtained--we must fight! I repeat it, sir, we must fight! An appeal to arms and to the God of hosts is all that is left us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They tell us, sir, that we are weak; unable to cope with so formidable an adversary. But when shall we be stronger? Will it be the next week, or the next year? Will it be when we are totally disarmed, and when a British guard shall be stationed in every house? Shall we gather strength by irresolution and inaction? Shall we acquire the means of effectual resistance by lying supinely on our backs and hugging the delusive phantom of hope, until our enemies shall have bound us hand and foot? Sir, we are not weak if we make a proper use of those means which the God of nature hath placed in our power. The millions of people, armed in the holy cause of liberty, and in such a country as that which we possess, are invincible by any force which our enemy can send against us. Besides, sir, we shall not fight our battles alone. There is a just God who presides over the destinies of nations, and who will raise up friends to fight our battles for us. The battle, sir, is not to the strong alone; it is to the vigilant, the active, the brave. Besides, sir, we have no election. If we were base enough to desire it, it is now too late to retire from the contest. There is no retreat but in submission and slavery! Our chains are forged! Their clanking may be heard on the plains of Boston! The war is inevitable--and let it come! I repeat it, sir, let it come.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in vain, sir, to extenuate the matter. Gentlemen may cry, Peace, Peace-- but there is no peace. The war is actually begun! The next gale that sweeps from the north will bring to our ears the clash of resounding arms! Our brethren are already in the field! Why stand we here idle? What is it that gentlemen wish? What would they have? Is life so dear, or peace so sweet, as to be purchased at the price of chains and slavery? Forbid it, Almighty God! I know not what course others may take; but as for me, give me liberty or give me death!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 1775 01:03:28 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/1775/03/23/give-me-liberty/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/1775/03/23/give-me-liberty/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
